Hari Kiran Yalavarthi

Ph: 404-993-8536 | Email: harikiranyalavarthi9@gmail.com

Summary

Passionate Software Engineer with more than 3 years of experience developing web applications, utilities, and testing tools in an agile environment using JavaScript ES6+, Typescript, React.js, Angular 1.x, Node.js, Express, REST API's, PostgreSQL, and MongoDB.

Work Experience

Software Engineer, Tricentis - Atlanta, GA

Feb 2018 to present

- Develop internal products and utilities/tools for customers using ES6+, React.js, Node.js, Express, PostgreSQL, MongoDB, REST API's, and Webpack.
- Built internal migration tools to migrate customers test artifacts from our competitors like HPQC, Zephyr, TestRail to qTest Manager product.
- Developed features for qTest Scenario JIRA add-on for BDD using Pug.js, Node.js, Express, and MongoDB.
- Created Agile & DevOps workflows for continuous testing using CI/CD tools like Jenkins/Bamboo/TeamCity/CircleCI, GitHub/Bitbucket/GitLab, Slack/Microsoft Teams, JavaScript ES6, qTest Pulse, qTest Manager, REST API's, and Jira.

Software Engineer Intern, KMS Technology, Inc. - Atlanta, GA

Jun 2017 to Jan 2018

- Developed front-end modules of the Kobiton product which helps to perform manual and automation testing on real mobile devices hosted in cloud using HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript ES6, Reactstrap, React.js, and, REST API's.
- Wrote automation scripts using Appium, Kobiton, Java to test native, hybrid and mobile-web applications.
- Assisted in data migration testing to validate successful migration from HP QC/ALM to qTest Manager.

Graduate Research Assistant, Georgia State University - Atlanta, GA

Aug 2016 to May 2017

- Worked on a Data Visualization project with Professor Dr. Ying Zhu, funded by Creative Media Industries Institute.
- The focus was on building visualizations based on Cricket game statistics using React.js, Recharts library, ES6.
- Performed web scraping on a popular cricket website (ESPNcricinfo) using jQuery, Node.js, Express, MongoDB to
 extract real-time data for visualizations.
- Worked as a lab instructor and grader for Java and Web development courses.

Software Developer Intern, Navtech - Hyderabad, India

Jan 2016 to Jun 2016

- Developed a web application for a restaurant client in a team of three developers using HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, JavaScript, and Angular 1.x.
- Designed and Developed RESTful API's for communication using Node.js, Express, Mongoose, and MongoDB.
- Integrated sessions, token-based, OAuth (Facebook) authentications into the web application with the help of Passport, JWT, and Express.

Education

Georgia State University - Atlanta, GA

Aug 2016 to Dec 2017

Master of Science in Computer Science

Osmania University - Hyderabad, India

Oct 2012 to June 2016

Bachelor of Engineering in Computer Science

Skills

Programming Languages: C, Java, Python.

JavaScript Stack: ES6+, TypeScript, React.js, Angular 1.x, Node.js, Express.js, Pug.js, D3.js, Loopback.

Web: HTML5, CSS3, Bootstrap4, jQuery, Ajax, PHP, SCSS, Gulp, Webpack.

Databases: PostgreSQL, MongoDB, MySQL.

Other: Git, Jira, Confluence, Jenkins, Appium, JMeter, Linux, Docker, Heroku, Wireshark.